Lionel Kubwimana

{ Full-Stack Ruby/Javascript Developer }

I am a self-taught Software Engineer passionate about automation. I have a background in Network Engineering and 3 years of work experience. I have mainly written code to build tools which make the everyday life of my coworkers much more easier. Available from January for new opportunities.

lionel.kubwimana@gmail.com

06 15 44 29 22

Paris, France

www.github.com/lionel-k

www.linkedin.com/in/l-kubwimana in

WORK EXPERIENCE

Network & Software Engineer

Covage

09/2014 - 09/2017

Telco operator specialized in fiber deployment and IP services.

Paris, France

- Lead developper of two in-house projects involving the automation of the network. Responsible of the code, strategy, vision, roadmap and feature definition. Using an infrastructure as code and a provider agnostic mindset.
- Level 3 Support Escalation for the Network Operation Center team.
- Testing, validating and writing technical documentation describing new IP services and solutions to be deployed on the MPLS/FTTH Covage network.

Reference: Sebastien Maillet (Network Director) – sebastien.maillet@covage.com

Network Engineer Intern

Covage

01/2014 - 06/2014

Paris, France

Tasks/Achievements

- Automated the management of the network configurations to be used for a specific customer request. The tool developed generate the needful configurations files for the routers, the switches and the CPEs.
- Built a network configuration audit tool. It checks the incoherences due to manual provisionning of the existing services.

Reference: Sebastien Maillet (Network Director) – sebastien.maillet@covage.com

Software Engineer Intern

Covage

07/2012 - 12/2012

Paris, France

- Designed a tool used for scheduled planned works on the fibers to identify and inform the customers affected by the fiber cut. It improved the existing process from one working day to 30 minutes.
- Developed an user-friendly interface giving the outline of parts of the network using the Google Maps API and queries to a GIS database containing the entire Covage fiber network.

Reference: Vincent Hurtes (Chief Information Officer) – vincent.hurtes@covage.com

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Web Developer

Le Wagon, 9-week intensive coding bootcamp

10/2017 - 12/2017

Paris, France

COURSES

- Ruby, Ruby on Rails
- Web scrapping, API
- HTML, CSS and best practices in web-design
- Database architecture, SQL
- Javascript JOuerv
- Git, GitHub, Heroku, Stripe, Mandrill, Algolia

Network Engineer's Degree

Université de Technologie de Troyes

09/2011 - 06/2014

Troyes, France

Computer Engineering, Exchange Semester

Nanyang Technological University

06/2013 - 12/2013 Singapore

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Scripting: Python, Perl

Linux CLI

Tools: Sublime Text, Git/Bitbucket, Trello

Configuration Management: Yaml, Jinja2

Networking Stack: Ethernet, TCP/IP Model, HTTP

Web Development: HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP,

Providers: Cisco, RAD, Redback Ericsson, Calix E7

PROJECTS

Automated Network Service Provisioning

Web-based application used by the Network Operation team to configure and activate a service without any access to the CLI of the network equipments.

Network Configuration Audit

Python scripts that check if the configuration of the network equipments is done according to the specifications described by the engineering team.

SOFT SKILLS

Interpersonal Relationships

Intercultural and interreligious awareness and openness aiming for a more united world.

Lifelong Learner

Constantly learning and gaining more knowledge with Coursera, Medium, Quora, Duolingo, TED Talks, Pocket.

Group Leading

Guiding teenagers to make life decisions and embrace perspectives that build a more fraternal world.

LANGUAGES

Full professional proficiency

French

Native or Bilingual

Italian

Elementary proficiency

Kirundi

Native or Bilinaual

INTERESTS

Reading (Inspirational books)

Music (Guitar & Choir)

Travelling

Hungarian Language

Sport (Running)